<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GE | WONG Jin Yung</title>
    <link>https://jinyung.github.io/tag/ge/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jinyung.github.io/tag/ge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>GE</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2026 Wong Jin Yung</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jinyung.github.io/images/icon_hud9e986e855b8e3846c4fec80f7a61c84_40920_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>GE</title>
      <link>https://jinyung.github.io/tag/ge/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life sciences</title>
      <link>https://jinyung.github.io/courses/life_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinyung.github.io/courses/life_science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-code&#34;&gt;Course code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;GEAE2514B&lt;/code&gt; (undergrad), under general education courses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;semesters-taught&#34;&gt;Semesters taught&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;113-1, 113-2, 114-1 (offered regularly every semester)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cover half of this general education course, focusing on the evolution of organisms and their interactions with each other and with the environments they inhabit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class is designed for non-biology majors and introduces students to the fascinating world of living organisms. I aim to show that life sciences are highly relatable and touch on fundamental questions related to our own existence and daily life. I also connect life sciences to other disciplines, so students from different majors can see how these ideas connect with their fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the topics I will cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution by natural selection is a big idea. Where did it come from?
Influences on Charles Darwin, including economic theories of resource competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Charles Darwin&amp;rsquo;s theory of evolution is not just about &amp;ldquo;survival of the fittest&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutation can cause cancer, yet without it long term evolution is impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survival of the luckiest: not all evolutionary changes are adaptations;
some are simply the outcome of random sampling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nature vs. Nurture: If evolution acts only on genes, does choice still matter?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To fight or not to fight? Peace benefits everyone, but why it is so hard to
maintain and why doesn&amp;rsquo;t aggression take over entirely in nature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If evolution acts on individual rather than group survival,
how can cooperation and even self-sacrificial behavior evolve?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why have peacocks evolved a large, colorful tail that handicaps them?
How sexual selection explains &amp;ldquo;illogical&amp;rdquo; mate choice in animals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the human population continue to grow? What limits it, and
how does it compare to other organisms?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do animal populations cycle or fluctuate? The link to the &amp;ldquo;the butterfly effect&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If extinction is natural, why should we save species? If survival of the fittest
rules nature, why save the losers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The race to resource exploitation: are we doomed,
or can we escape &amp;ldquo;the tragedy of the commons&amp;rdquo;? Is reducing consumption the answer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How close are we to climate tipping points? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t we notice them coming earlier?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None. My classes are quite different from high school biology. It doesn’t matter much whether you have studied biology before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The origin of species and the tree of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal behavior, conflicts and cooperation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexual selection and evolution summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Population and community ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Anthropocene and conservation biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
